<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emotion on Coltan Scrivner</title>
    <link>/tags/emotion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emotion on Coltan Scrivner</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/emotion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cognitive Architecture of Hatred</title>
      <link>/project/hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/hatred/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hatred has existed across cultures and throughout human history. It is often pointed to as a source of many social ills, including violence, oppression, indifference to suffering, dehumanization, and abusive or threatening speech. But what is hatred, and what sorts of behaviors might it motivate? After all, behavioral outcomes like violence, oppression, and abusive speech can result from a variety of motivations. What makes outcomes motivated by hatred different? If hatred is a distinct motivation, then a better understanding of its cognitive landscape, including its causes and consequences, is needed. A more comprehensive understanding of these causes and consequences will lead to more informed peacebuilding between individuals, populations, and nations. This project aims to elaborate both theoretically and empirically on the emotion of hate. In particular, we are interested in describing the evolved function of hatred as a cognitive motivational system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on a theoretical framework and collecting qualitative data on experiences of hatred and the dispositions people have towards those who the hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=iUg3iLUAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aaron Sell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.wsu.edu/evolutionary-politics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anthony Lopez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poster-from-our-seminar-at-the-inception-of-this-project&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poster from our seminar at the inception of this project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and Evolutionary Function of Shame</title>
      <link>/project/shame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/shame/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Evidence suggests that shame is a neurocognitive adaptation that helps counter social devaluation. If this is true, then shame should be elicited when someone thinks you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong, even when no actual wrongdoing has occurd. In this project we are evaluating the role of the (mis)informed audience in eliciting shame. We are also using &lt;a href=&#34;https://pupil-labs.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eye tracking&lt;/a&gt; to investigate social information gathering processes that are triggered when someone is being devalued or shamed. The next steps for this project will involve analyzing hormonal mediator of shame behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielsznycer.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Daniel Sznycer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poster-presented-at-hbes-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poster presented at HBES 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can click the poster to download it from OSF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/395g2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
