<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Coltan Scrivner</title>
    <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Coltan Scrivner</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/coltanscrivner.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cognitive Architecture of Hatred</title>
      <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/hatred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coltanscrivner.com/project/hatred/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Hatred has existed across cultures and throughout human history. It is often pointed to as a source of many social ills, including violence, oppression, indifference to suffering, dehumanization, and abusive or threatening speech. But what is hatred, and what sorts of behaviors might it motivate? After all, behavioral outcomes like violence, oppression, and abusive speech can result from a variety of motivations. What makes outcomes motivated by hatred different? If hatred is a distinct motivation, then a better understanding of its cognitive landscape, including its causes and consequences, is needed. A more comprehensive understanding of these causes and consequences will lead to more informed peacebuilding between individuals, populations, and nations. This project aims to elaborate both theoretically and empirically on the emotion of hate. In particular, we are interested in describing the evolved function of hatred as a cognitive motivational system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on a theoretical framework and collecting qualitative data on experiences of hatred and the dispositions people have towards those who the hate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=iUg3iLUAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aaron Sell&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://labs.wsu.edu/evolutionary-politics/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Anthony Lopez&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poster-from-our-seminar-at-the-inception-of-this-project&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poster from our seminar at the inception of this project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gruesomeness and Perceived Formidability</title>
      <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/gruesome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coltanscrivner.com/project/gruesome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Executions throughout history have taken many forms. For most of this time, state executions were grisly, often public, events. In times of war, placing an enemy&amp;rsquo;s severed head on a spike can serve as a powerful warning against potential invaders. Even in modern times, extremist groups will capture gruesome executions on video for the sole purpose of distribution. Why is this the case? While deterrance is likely one reason for gruesomeness, it&amp;rsquo;s not clear why this works better as a deterrant than other methods, nor is it clear that deterrance is the only reason for gruesome actions. In this project, we are exploring the possibility that gruesome actions increase the viewier&amp;rsquo;s cognitive representation of the perpetrator&amp;rsquo;s formidability. In other words, perhaps committing a gruesome action increases how formidable you are in the minds of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danielmtfessler.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Daniel Fessler&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cholbrook01.bol.ucla.edu&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Colin Holbrook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanisms and Evolutionary Function of Shame</title>
      <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/shame/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coltanscrivner.com/project/shame/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Evidence suggests that shame is a neurocognitive adaptation that helps counter social devaluation. If this is true, then shame should be elicited when someone thinks you&amp;rsquo;ve done something wrong, even when no actual wrongdoing has occurd. In this project we are evaluating the role of the (mis)informed audience in eliciting shame. We are also using &lt;a href=&#34;https://pupil-labs.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;eye tracking&lt;/a&gt; to investigate social information gathering processes that are triggered when someone is being devalued or shamed. The next steps for this project will involve analyzing hormonal mediator of shame behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This project is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielsznycer.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Daniel Sznycer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;poster-presented-at-hbes-2019&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poster presented at HBES 2019&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can click the poster to download it from OSF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/395g2/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;poster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Allure of Violence</title>
      <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/allure-of-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coltanscrivner.com/project/allure-of-violence/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Discussions of violence and initiatives to curb it pervade modern political and social discourses across much of the world. However, there is still a lack of rich, interdisciplinary explanations of how people perceive, process, and make meaning from experiences of violence. While past research has focused on investigating how people understand violent conflicts and how exposure to violence relates to behavioral and life outcomes, virtually no work has been conducted on how visual attention to interpersonal violence relates to interpretation and rationalization of what is being seen. This two-year project utilizes an innovative mixed-methods approach in which we combine eye tracking and verbal descriptions to better understand how people extract and construct meaning from violent social interactions. We are also exploring the role of life experiences, such as exposure to community violence, and individual differences on visual and cognitive biases that occur when viewing violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://neubauercollegium.uchicago.edu/faculty/understanding_the_meaning_making_of_violence_bridging_perception_cognition/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the Neubauer Collegium for Culture and Society&lt;/a&gt; and is in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://psychology.uchicago.edu/directory/marc-g-berman&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marc Berman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://voices.uchicago.edu/bermanlab/choe/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kyoung whan Choe&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://humdev.uchicago.edu/directory/richard-shweder&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rick Shweder&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://marquette.academia.edu/GabrielVelez&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gabe Velez&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://primate.uchicago.edu/dario-maestripieri.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dario Maestripieri &lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-allure-of-violence-conference&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Allure of Violence Conference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;conference.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To kick off this project, we hosted a conference in which we invited a wide range of scholars, including psychologists, novelists, artists, anthropologists, engineers, and others to discuss the allure of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out photos from the first part of the day &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/neubauercollegium/albums/72157703156661834&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on the Neubauer Collegium&amp;rsquo;s flickr page for the conference&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conference even included a live stage-fight! Courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.colum.edu/academics/faculty/david-wooley.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fight Master David Woolley and his students&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;preprint&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preprint&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find our first preprint from this project &lt;a href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/3y4w9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;on PsyArXiv&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://psyarxiv.com/3y4w9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;preprint.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horror, Cognition, and Play</title>
      <link>/coltanscrivner.com/project/haunt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coltanscrivner.com/project/haunt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Every October, millions of people pay to be scared in haunted houses, or &amp;ldquo;haunts.&amp;rdquo; On its surface, this is a strange phenomenon. Why do we pay to engage in entertainment that frightens us? We approach this question from the perspective of play. Both imaginative and active, haunts allow people, in this case adults, to bond with others through mechanisms curiously similar to play seen in other areas of human life. In this project we tested the idea that some individuals enjoy the haunt more because they perceive it to be comfortably unpredictable, as opposed to uncomfortably unpredictable (frightening) or predictable (boring). We suspected there would be a sweet spot, so to speak, in scariness that maximizes the perception of the haunt as a form of play. To test this, we used heart rate monitors and trap cameras to monitor enjoyment and anticipation of the scares through physiological measures, facial expressions coded for emotion, and self reported experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The research was carried out at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/DystopiaEntertainment/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dystopia Haunted House&lt;/a&gt; while I was a visiting researcher at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://interactingminds.au.dk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interacting Minds Centre at Aarhus University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;This project was in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;http://pure.au.dk/portal/en/persons/mathias-clasen(3c9b0961-b1e9-4084-867f-d8b959ba40e5).html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mathias Clasen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://pure.au.dk/portal/en/persons/id(67f068d6-a98a-4f2b-840c-53b8855192de).html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marc Andersen&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://pure.au.dk/portal/en/us@teo.au.dk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Uffe Schjødt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;here-are-some-photos-from-the-project&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are some photos from the project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;p1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;p2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;p3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;p4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;p5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;p6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
